You know how when we have a storm, we
give it a name like storm Boris or
Shandra or something? Well, we're now
doing the same thing for heat waves, but
we're naming them after fossil fuel
companies. And as this is the second
heatwave of the year, it starts with the
letter B for BP. Letter A stood for
Aramco. So, let me tell you a fun fact
about BP. You know the concept of a
carbon footprint. You might think that
this was developed by some kind of
environmentalist. Well, not quite. It
was actually developed as part of a $200
million marketing and PR campaign by BP
to try and make the general public feel
guilty about our everyday life choices
rather than say get angry at the people
actually producing all of the fossil
fuels in the first place. So I looked up
the carbon footprint of BP and it sits
at around 300 million tons of CO2 per
year. And historically BP alone are
responsible for 2.13% of all carbon
emissions throughout history, which is
quite impressive for a single company.
So stay safe in the heatwave.